6798 N. HOURGLASS DR.
COEUR D'ALENE, ID 83815
(208) 755-7364
CARSONMAGEE@YAHOO.COM
LinkedIn.com/in/CarsonMagee

CARSON MAGEE



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate Computer Scientist with 8+ years in customer service and client support. Collaborated with, and led team members through the founding of two businesses and worked as a technical lead of a yearbook staff for 3 years. Dedicated over 1,500 hours towards volunteer work with practical knowledge of communication, collaboration and teamwork, as well as the co-author of a professional computer science journal publication.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficiency of Software Development in C Strong Technical Writing Skills

Working knowledge of HTML, CSS, and Python Background in Agile and Scrum Techniques

Adept User Experience Designer Proficient with the Adobe Creative Suite

Exceptional Public Speaking Abilities Understanding of Photography

EXPERIENCE

Carson Magee Photography, Coeur d'Alene, ID — Founder/Owner

- APRIL 2017 - PRESENT

- Founder of a photography business communicating with over 60 clients, including the Office of Mayor, Spokane, WA
- Photographer for weddings, senior portraits, company events, couples/engagement, and family photos.

Pockets Productions, Coeur d'Alene, ID — Co-Founder/Co-Owner

- MAY 2014 - PRESENT

 Co-founder of an entertainment business performing for 10+ large companies and businesses, including Kroger Company, Exxon Mobil Corporation, Festival of Sandpoint, Little People of America Incorporated, URM Stores Incorporated, and Northern Quest Casino

Quest Summer Day Camp, Coeur d'Alene, ID — Counselor

— SUMMER 2021 & SUMMER 2022

- Successfully led a group of 30 4th and 5th graders through teamwork skills to communicate and troubleshoot difficult situations
- Planned and taught daily lessons, guided outdoor field trips, and executed medical practices as a CPR, AED, and First Aid trained staff member

Blue Zone Marketing, Coeur d'Alene, ID — Social Media Lead

— OCTOBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

- Collaborated with a group of 5 other team members to produce a full range of branding from blogs, to website creation, to logo design, for 20+ direct clients
- Fully managed social media platforms for clients by creating social media posts from scratch in Canva,
 Photoshop, and similar software applications and styling instagram galleries
- Time management was crucial in the completion of deadlines while delivering 8 to 10 technical products a day

Figpickels Toy Emporium, Coeur d'Alene, ID — Sales Clerk/Floor Expert

- MARCH 2018 - MAY 2020

- Effectively communicated and trained other employees in product knowledge
- Handled thousands of transactions as a sales clerk
- Improved customer service through networking, effectively communicating, and interpersonal connections

EDUCATION

Boise State University — Computer Science, Cyber Security Emphasis — AUG. 2022 - PRESENT, BOISE, ID

North Idaho College/University of Idaho — Computer Science — AUG. 2021 - MAY 2022, COEUR D'ALENE, ID

Coeur d'Alene High School — Graduated Honors, Dual Credit — AUG. 2017 - JUNE 2021, COEUR D'ALENE, ID

AWARDS/CERTIFICATES

STONE SCHOLARS COMPUTER SCIENCE ASSISTANTSHIP

- SPRING SEMESTER 2022, UNIVERSITY OF IDAHO

 Worked under Dr. Joules Beeston, University of Idaho computer science professor, as a research assistant to co-author a professional scientific journal publication on the relation of isomorphism in graph theory and common logic games such as sudoku and tic-tac-toe

YEARBOOK EDITOR IN CHIEF

--- AUG. 2020 - JUNE 2021, COEUR D'ALENE, ID

- Effectively led a staff of 16 students to produce a published yearbook
- Portrayed patience and determination to communicate effectively with the publishing company
- Organized and set effective deadlines

PHI THETA KAPPA HONORS SOCIETY

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP CERTIFIED

- May 2017, COEUR D'ALENE, ID

VOLUNTEER WORK

JUVENILE DIABETES RESEARCH FOUNDATION (JDRF) -

- 100+ Speaking Engagements on Behalf of JDRF (National & Local Television, Magazine, Newspaper, Podcast)
- National Design Contest Winner (Ford Motor Company)
- Walk to Cure Diabetes Youth Ambassador
- Collaborated With the State Governor to Establish an Annual Proclamation for a Type One Diabetes Awareness Day in the State of Idaho
- Spoke on Capitol Hill and Participated in a Senate Hearing